

Senior level marketing professional with an MBA and extensive experience in B2B marketing strategy for high-profile and strategic programs. Consultative partner with a strong combination of strengths in market strategy and delivering integrated marketing campaigns that provide solid return on investment, grow revenue, build brand awareness and increase sales funnel activity for both emerging and established markets.

EXPERTISE

Market Strategy Segmentation Agency Management Communications Product Marketing Civic Leadership Brand Management Demand Generation Public Relations SEO, SEM Loyalty & Retention Channel Support Customer Engagement Event Production Event Fundraising

EDUCATION

2008 MBA, Marketing & Strategy

University of Kansas

2000 BBA, Marketing

University of Texas at Austin

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2007 - PRESENT // SPRINT // OVERLAND PARK, KS & BEND, OR

Manager, Sales Segment Strategy (2013-present; Bend, OR)

Partner with sales, sales operations, marketing, and product teams to identify and successfully launch market opportunities for products/ services and technologies within the segment. Develop business models for new products/services. Own P&L for the segment, driving alignment of product plans, marketing plans/communications, sales plans, training, and other support mechanisms.

- Align organizational resources to secure support and funding for building new product lines and functionality to support long term revenue goals
- Facilitate collaboration among functional groups to ensure alignment to strategy, particularly when competing priorities exist.

Wholesale Marketing Manager (2009-2011, 2012-2013)

Built and executed all external marketing programs, media and sales support programs for Sprint Wholesale Solutions, a \$1.5+ Billion business unit. Specific responsibilities included agency management, acquisition marketing strategy & execution, content strategy, and solution bundling and positioning. Recommend and executed tactical plans across six industry segments including messaging, presentations, videos, whitepapers and other content materials, interactive sales tools, collateral, tradeshow engagement, and website. Led relationship with corporate communications and public relations.

- Led marketing communication strategies & execution across six market segments including global markets, retail, and technology solutions providers
- Led go-to-market communications planning & execution for all wholesale solutions
- Led brand, positioning & creative campaign evolution efforts for Wholesale business unit
- Chosen to participate in NO&W Leadership Development Program for 2010-2011

Product Marketing Manager, 4G & Network Vision (2011-2012)

Drove marketing & communication strategies for Sprint's Network Vision initiative, a multi-year, strategic priority for the company. Drove key messaging decisions, working with all channels for internal and external communication. Coordinated cross-functional objectives related to marketing communications, media, analyst and public relations, channel support and sales enablement.

- Supported multiple executive-level communications and channel execution for major initiative announcements
- Coordinated company-wide communication strategies for both internal and external audiences

Channel Marketing Manager (2008 – 2009) Consultant at Sprint, Streffco (2007 - 2008)

Developed and implemented both acquisition and retention marketing plans for Sprint Wholesale customers to address changing consumer buying behavior, with primary focus toward online marketing and front-line channel incentive programs. Provided thought leadership and valuable customer and marketing insight regarding trends, behavioral shifts, and attitudinal dynamics. Fuel account growth through consultative relationships, business model evaluation, and building comarketing programs to drive incremental subscribers.

- Front-line channel sales incentives generated over \$5 Million in incremental revenue (2008-2009) through an 18% lift in gross sales (120% of goal)
- Executed new segmentation strategy to achieve 20% increase in conversion rates and a 6% increase in ARPU
- Initiated efforts to enter the online marketing space, including SEO, micro-site development, and customer engagement

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (cont)

2004 - 2007 // EVENT 360 // OVERLAND PARK, KS

General Manger (2006-2007)

Led client strategy and budget development for Run-Walk-Ride fundraising events driving increased cause awareness, participant engagement, and fundraising. Responsible for project management: staff management, timeline, budget, and work progress from functional departments including Marketing, Creative Services, Event Production, Volunteer Services, Participant Recruitment and Retention.

Production Manager, Breast Cancer 3-Day (2004-2006)

Oversaw all logistics and planning of 3-Day, 60-mile fundraising walk with 30+ event sites and an \$800,000 budget benefiting breast cancer charities. Identified and negotiated contracts for all sites, vendors, municipal permits, and safety support. Provided leadership to 6 local staff, 60 touring staff, and 300-person volunteer force in event production and execution.

- Produced athletic fundraising events with 1,000 participants (2005) and 1,500 participants (2006) generating \$6.6 million over 2 years.
- Implemented formal project management practices to realize increased project efficiencies
- Developed and executed project plans for both the largest (\$20 Million) and smallest (\$20,000) projects within the organization; projects required creativity, efficient production, and minimization of resource allocation
- Developed business case for the implementation of GPS technology for national event series, estimated long-term cost savings exceeds \$30,000/year for national events

2003 - 2004 // OVERLAND PARK CHAMBER OF COMMERCE // OVERLAND PARK, KS Program Director

Oversaw all member acquisition and retention responsibilities for 1100 members with \$600,000 in annual dues. Managed all aspects of event planning for signature events and trade shows including logistics, marketing, implementation, and execution. Developed educational programs to meet member needs, particularly in education and civic leadership.

- Transformed event management practices to align with organization's strategic direction and goals
- Developed a small business seminar series utilizing volunteer presenters (net income: \$10,000/year)
- Increased awareness, applications and, therefore, net revenue generated by Leadership Overland Park by over \$10,000
- Doubled facility rentals via increased marketing and awareness (net increase: \$15,000)
- Increased event attendance and income over the previous year by \$12,000

2002 - 2003 // GREATER AUSTIN CHAMBER OF COMMERCE // AUSTIN, TX Director, Investor Relations

Implemented and maintained all retention activities for approximately 2000 members in a non-profit, economic development and business organization. Executed all retention efforts for member companies that account for nearly \$1 million in annual donations and contributions to economic development and quality-of-life capital campaigns. Facilitated all activities of the Chamber's Ambassador committee – consisting of 65+ business volunteers interacting with new and established members to aid in retention efforts. Recruited, trained, and managed in excess of 250 volunteers annually.

 Coordinated membership renewal campaign in which 100 volunteers made 1300 personal visits to members. Campaign generated \$687,000 in early membership renewals, exceeding goal by 10%.

2000 - 2001 // MCI WORLDCOM // OVERLAND PARK, KS Global Client Services Manager (2001)

Protected and maximized revenue from an account base of global customers with recurring monthly revenues exceeding \$500,000. Optimized current services and pursued additional growth opportunities.

Project Manager (2001)

Managed a team of 16 Sales Executives, Project Managers and client executives to ensure policy compliance for a \$20 Million, custom, telecommunications network implementation.

Global Account Representative (2000)

Participated in extensive sales, sales support, and product training.

- Achieved 1000% of assigned sales quota (10 times goal) and 150% of 2001 assigned billing quota
- Ranked #1 nationally in my position for the Global Accounts Division based on quota performance
- Named to WorldCom President's Club in November 2001

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Boys & Girls Club of Central Oregon

Member, Board of Directors

Sprint Community Partners

United Way, Young Leaders Society
WISE—Women in Sprint Excelling (Employee Resource Group)
March for Babies, Wholesale Marketing Ambassador (2009)

Junior League of Kansas City, MO

Board of Directors—Step-Up, Director of Marketing (2013-2014) Leadership Institute, Chair (2012-2013) Dinner Club Co-Chair & New Fundraiser Marketing Chair (2011-2012) Various other committees (2001, 2003-2011)